export const topick1 = [
  {
    question: 'When was the port of Ostend founded?',
    options: {
      a: '1200',
      b: '1265',
      c: '1350',
    },
    answer: '1265',
  },
  {
    question: 'In what year did Ostend become a free port?',
    options: {
      a: '1722',
      b: '1830',
      c: '1865',
    },
    answer: '1865',
  },
  {
    question: 'Who built the first harbor of Ostend?',
    options: {
      a: 'Count of Flanders',
      b: 'King of Spain',
      c: 'Duke of Burgundy',
    },
    answer: 'Count of Flanders',
  },
  {
    question: 'What structure was built in Ostend to protect against pirates?',
    options: {
      a: "Napoleon's Fortress",
      b: "Lion's Gate",
      c: 'Dragon Tower',
    },
    answer: "Napoleon's Fortress",
  },
  {
    question:
      'What important sea route passed through Ostend in the 18th century?',
    options: {
      a: 'Route to India',
      b: 'Route to America',
      c: 'Route to Africa',
    },
    answer: 'Route to India',
  },
  {
    question: 'In what year did Ostend receive city status?',
    options: {
      a: '1445',
      b: '1584',
      c: '1700',
    },
    answer: '1584',
  },
  {
    question: 'What event occurred in Ostend in 1604?',
    options: {
      a: 'Establishment of the first lighthouse',
      b: 'Capture of the city by the Spanish',
      c: 'Opening of the first fish market',
    },
    answer: 'Capture of the city by the Spanish',
  },
  {
    question: 'Who was William Witte?',
    options: {
      a: 'The first mayor of Ostend',
      b: 'Captain of the first merchant ship',
      c: 'Architect of the port',
    },
    answer: 'Captain of the first merchant ship',
  },
  {
    question: 'In what year was the Ostend Company founded?',
    options: {
      a: '1717',
      b: '1789',
      c: '1848',
    },
    answer: '1717',
  },
  {
    question: 'What important event happened in Ostend in 1838?',
    options: {
      a: 'Opening of the first railway line',
      b: 'Construction of the new port',
      c: 'Establishment of the maritime college',
    },
    answer: 'Construction of the new port',
  },
];
